I think this guy was riding by the seat of his pants here, but he sprung the trap at
what looks like either $7.5 or $15 million are all considered a good day for him.
Nice work there, Chris.
You're a pseudonymous version of Chris that actually executed this attack.
You won't admit to it, but can't get along with him, but you could delegate work to
him.
Are you asking if I have developed a Jackson-style parasocial relationship with Claude?
Is that the question?
Not imply quite Jackson level because I think that's like extreme.
Like I think that there's a little bit of like almost like quasi-romantic, but like
on an emotional level, not on a physical level.
Yeah.
Oh, we're about to break 10.
Jeez, it just popped from six.
It was six, like two minutes ago.
This time, you need to, you need to do the next one.
I think Jared just got wrecked on chain again and then we're getting a dividend from GTO.
All right, we're lives.
What's up, everybody?
It's Jackson Cook and we've got our boys.
What up, it's Tyler.
And also Chris.
And Chris still probably has thumb issues.
Chris, how, how is the thumb going?
So brace off today.
I can't tell if it's getting better or worse, but you know, I've just decided, you know,
as we talked about last podcast, so this is something I'm going to have to live with because
it's either this crippling thumb issue or the keyboard, and I've made my decision.
So you've just, just disregarded Dr. Tyler's recommendation.
Yeah, I think I'm just going to truck through it.
I think it's, I think it's getting better, but it's been this way for a while, so it
could be illusory.
And Tyler, are you a doctor?
Because on, you know, which jurisdiction we're talking about, but in this jurisdiction now,
in the jurisdiction of the podcast, maybe.
Oh yeah, but maybe the pain doctor is of all the burns you dish out.
Okay.
And, uh, I don't know.
Let's get straight into it.
We're going to drop into purple fortune, Chris.
It's purple fortune going.
Okay.
Yeah.
We're trying something a little bit new this time where in the past with purple fortune,
we had Claude go off and like do some market research and come up with a trade idea and
then tell us why.
But I thought it would be like a little bit more fun to have Claude read our outline and
our topics for the episode and then choose a thematic perp to invest in.
So it's, you know, tied in with the episode.
And so based on this one, Claude chose that we should long Gito and the thesis here is
hold the sandwich.
All right.
So, uh, Gito is a token on Solana, uh, basically, okay.
This week the market learned MEV is in a crime.
It's a cashflow.
Gito runs 95% of Solana staking, takes the majority of priority fee volume and just shipped
a terminal that routes the skim back to token holders.
Meanwhile, the most feared independent sandwich operator on a theorem just got liquidated
by his own approvals in our tistle.
The artisanal era of MEV is dying and the incorporated era is consolidating.
You are not betting on extraction.
You were betting that extraction pays a dividend and monopolies at the toll booth get rerated.
All right.
That sounds like a solid thesis to me, will it play out over the course of an hour?
I'm not really here.
I mean, it's doing great.
Like I don't, I don't know if this has anything to do with the timing and, uh, you know, goodness
of the research, but, uh, this might be our best one.
Like it, it's not close.
We just have to write it all episode.
I mean, the first episode we were up like 20 or $30 on our, um, oh, yeah, that was the,
yeah.
The, um, the semiconductor trade or the high performance memory.
Yeah.
D ram.
Before we were one liquidated it, oh man, we only went five X though.
We could, we could be up a whole $6 if we had gone, you know, five X, we could be a
week on 25 X, I know, I know.
And the reason for that is because of fables guardrails.
I'm just, I just tell you now, I'll tell you now, Fable was like, bro, I won't let you
gamble with more than five X leverage.
Yeah.
So I accidentally started it in not dangerously skip permissions mode.
I started it in auto mode and the guardrails were just like, it wouldn't let me place the
trade.
It wouldn't let me do it at 10 X.
So I was like, you know, whilst we're talking about on-chain fund movements, I was furiously,
uh, trying to work out what was, what was wrong with him.
It turns out, yeah, wrong mode, but so if we used Kimmy K three for this Kimmy K three
would be like, have you tried a hundred X and can I please set this up for you, sir?
I feel like Kimmy K three like would like leverage.
It's just like, I get a feeling, you know, um, at least three X, you know?
Um, yeah, I feel like I learned so much about sandwich attacks from, uh, our AI selves.
Me too.
And like surprisingly little, uh, personal information was revealed by our AI counterparts,
which I appreciated deeply.
Uh, yeah, we're still calibrating that, you know, our, uh, the AI has developed a world
model of us and it has extracted our souls into the soul.md with such precision that
when I first generated the transcript, it leaked some, you know, personal information
from one of the hosts and put it into the public domain.
So we had to go back to the drawing board a little bit, had something to do with pastrami.
We were able to keep the metaphor in, but we had to take the rest out.
Yeah.
We had a very uncomfortable history of pastrami for someone in this podcast, so it was a little
bit of a trigger warning.
Um, yeah, I mean, speaking of more on the video, I had my girlfriend listen to the AI
voice and she says, it doesn't sound like me.
Have you guys had anybody listen to your AI voice and like heard what they have to say?
I mean, my mind doesn't sound like me at all.
But Tyler sounds exactly like him.
Like I can hear his headset in the AI recording.
I noticed that as well.
I didn't think it retrained either.
Like I didn't tell it to get the audio from the last episode and to retrain the voices.
So I thought I was going to be the same voices from the Presidio audio, but it does like
bake in my headset vibe into it.
That's awesome.
And then back to, you know, Mev and sandwich attacks, you know, was the AI was the AI accurate
and do we have more to add on it?
Yeah.
I was quite bang on.
Uh, it even, it revealed even extra details that I don't know where it got them.
Well, I've been your soul that you have so much knowledge about MEV that is deep in your
amygdala that fable somehow extracted.
Yeah.
I mean, it's weights and my weights were like, you know, overlapping just for this one thing,
maybe.
Um, yeah.
So I mean this particular exploit I think was notable for two reasons.
One, this is not the first time a Mev bot has been exploited.
There's a famous case of the low carb crusader, which Jared in particular managed to dodge
that one.
Uh, but secondly, this one was like extremely sophisticated.
So are all the Mev bots named after food?
Well, I guess that was a thing like food tokens were a thing as well.
I'm just getting hungry.
It's like naming all of these crypto things known for all of rhyming about food out of
nowhere.
There, there may be some like strange on chain pathology there now that I think about it.
I think it originally was sandwiches, right?
And then like, I don't know, uh, it's going on and on.
Uh, but, but in this particular one, so what the person did, the attacker is, so there's
this concept of wrapping tokens and they created basically a fake wrapped token that looked
comparable to a real one exposed to the ability to wrap, uh, into that token, uh, and created
like a compelling looking arbitrage option using that fake wrapped token.
So they seeded an arbitrage opportunity with this fake wrapped token.
Uh, so the Jared bot with, with its limited control, saw this wrapped token and this arbitrage
and was like, okay, under this heuristic, I'm just going to wrap into this, you know,
fake version of wrapped teeth and then pocket this arbitrage, which was like maybe wrapped
teeth and real USDC.
Right.
Um, so at the start, this fake wrapper was working as intended.
So the bot would wrap the eth it would go and pocket this arbitrage opportunity, take
a couple of bits, um, but in the code at a certain block height, I believe the wrapper
cut over to no longer pulling the funds.
It would just keep giving back these fake wrapped tokens and never pulling the funds
out of Jared's wallet, which you're thinking like, okay, that's free money.
No.
Uh, so it would accrue all of these approvals.
And then after, you know, the person who made this fake wrapper was satisfied with the hall,
they pulled all of the eth out of Jared's wallet with these standing approvals at one
time.
Uh, so the, the reason this works is because
That's how you do an exit scam though.
Right.
Is like you, you set the trap and then you wait until the, you know, the purse accumulates
and accumulates and accumulates.
And then you're like, okay, now's the time to rip the cord and you know, make my move
a hundred percent.
And the reason too greedy and wait too long, but you also don't want to be too, uh, you
know, if you give up too soon and reveal yourself and you leave money on the table, so to say
a hundred percent.
And I think this guy was riding by the seat of his pants here.
Um, but, uh, I like, he sprung the trap at what looks like either 7.5 or $15 million
or all considered, uh, a good day for him.
Nice work there.
Chris, I, you're, you're, uh, you know, pseudonymous version of Chris that actually executed
this attack.
He won't admit to it, but no, I have no, no knowledge that Chris black hats as a, uh,
I don't even know if this is black hat.
This is like kind of Robin hood E high feel to steal from a med bot is very like Robin
hood.
I bet.
I mean, they're not like well loved on chain, I will say.
So I think this was, yeah, yeah.
Um, so I think the, the community is very split over whether this was a good or a bad
thing.
All right.
And for the arbitrages in the sandwich, is it always within like that stack of transactions
or does it go across like multiple stacks of transactions to accomplish the arbitrage?
Uh, so in this case it was, uh, routing transactions across a couple of these fake pools.
So it was like a, I think a two or a three hop fake arbitrage.
Um, but like mev in general is not, you know, specific to single transaction, like often
transactions are bundled together into one to like achieve the desired outcome.
Man, Chris, are you a, uh, code is law guy or a laws law guy?
Am I like, I feel like when people see stuff like this, you know, I feel like the old,
the old guard would be like code is law, so whatever you can accomplish on the blockchain,
if you were able to accomplish, then like, you know, you're not like stealing from somebody,
you're just, you put, you both put your money into this machine that had rules and you like
discovered the rules better than they did.
And therefore there's like no actual wrongdoing here.
But then there's, you know, situations where almost all situations where the, you know,
the law and the physical world, if it's a big enough, um, you know, hall or something
that was perceived to have harmed people, they will intervene and charge people under,
you know, the laws of that land.
And that's a very different way to operate than the blockchain.
Um, and I feel like there's some, like a good example of this was the guy who attacked mango
markets.
Do you remember that one?
That one was like insane and very memorable to my mind, but it was kind of a similar thing
where this guy like figured out how to exploit this defy protocol and he extracted a bunch
of money and tokens.
And then he kind of like screwed with them on chain and left some like messages taunting
them.
And then eventually he got doxxed and now he's like in jail because they doxxed him and then
he got charged with like stealing money out of this defy protocol.
But at the end of the day, like the defy protocol had its rules and he like, you know, might
have exploited the rules in a way that they didn't want, but they made the rules.
He exploited them.
He got the money.
Uh, but then like the United States, Southern district in New York was like, no dog, you're,
you're Solana rules are meaningless are, are us government, you know, guns and Fiat taxes
rules are, are, are what matter here.
I think my morality is more sympathetic to the code is law side of that.
But then the pragmatic thing is don't do things that are going to get you thrown in jail and
the real world.
I completely agree with you.
I think it's case by case.
I think like in general, like ignoring the negative externalities of me giving this answer,
I would say I am a code is law guy, um, most of the time.
Uh, but you know, I think there are cases where like, you know, something has genuinely
been exploited in a way where maybe it is beneficial to, you know, prosecute like the
law is still the law, like the code is law, but the law is also the law.
Right?
So I think like, yeah, it's, it's, it's very case by case.
Yeah.
If the law is also the law though, then the blockchain is meaningless kind of way, because
like, if, if the law can come in and supersede the actions that happened on the blockchain,
and what's the point of the blockchain, it's, it's just like an open database that is controlled
by the government.
Um, like, yeah, I think, I think for me, the, the, the chain is like, uh, a parallel thread.
Right?
Like, I don't think we're ever going to get to a place where, um, I mean, maybe we will
get to a place where everything is perfectly regulated, uh, which might fit into our next
topic, but, um, yeah, I think like it's just going to be a very messy interplay, uh, especially
as things heat up between like code law, uh, and, uh, law, law, like, like with Dallas,
for example, actually, Chris, could you, are there any examples that you can remember where
you think that law, law should Trump, uh, code law?
Cause you said you think there are some, so there must be one that's happened or when
you can imagine like sanctions is a good example.
Like, you know, if somebody, if North Korea steals a bunch of money and then someone is
forced to freeze that money on chain, so they can't like develop nuclear weapons to threaten
innocent people.
I don't think a lot of people are too upset about that, but it does kind of fly in the
face of the idea of the blockchain.
I think, yeah, I think there's a piece about setting expectations here, right?
Like circles freeze function, for example, everybody knows that's there.
Uh, and like, that is like an extension of the law into the blockchain, right?
Um, where, where it sometimes gets questionable is like, you know, things like reorgs and
rollbacks, like, uh, with what something similar to what, with what arbitrary did with the
buy bit hack.
I think it was, um, I, I personally, I think that was a good move given like what arbitrary
professors to be, um, but yeah, that's a great example, Tyler, I totally agree.
Okay.
So I guess if like enough of the government powers agree and that like some entity is
bad, like North Korea, then we're okay with it interfering with the freedom of code and
the freedom of the blockchain is kind of what you're saying in the North Korea example.
Um, yeah, I just, I think like the system is what it does, right?
If the system freezes $300 million of North Korean assets, that's what the system is.
Um, yeah, for Bitcoin, I would prefer that Bitcoin remain such a ship resistant, but
I would never do anything to like enable a use case like that.
That is unlawful.
That's true.
Yeah.
For the record, me as well.
And our opinions are then do not reflect our employers.
Very least.
Yeah.
Speaking of the, the Kimmy, uh, Kimmy three, there's a lot of hype, Chris.
Have you tried it?
Why didn't you purple fortune with Kimmy three?
I tried to try it.
I think the only way that you can get it right now is through their website, kimmy.com, Kimmy,
something like that.
Um, and I, I swerved that, um, but from what I'm seeing on the internet, it's very good.
And what does it tell though, what's like real and what's just hype.
So I'll be a little bit of a bear here, but like, I think that it looks really good on
the benchmarks, but I feel like the open weight models are known to like, look better on the
benchmarks than they do in real life.
Um, because the benchmarks, at least the ones that are open are like very gameable, I think.
And they have a huge incentive to like make their models look good on the benchmarks.
And I think that the, that perception doesn't always meet reality.
And then the other thing I saw was that like they can reach these benchmarks, Kimmy can,
but it uses like 10 X the tokens to achieve the task as a better model.
So it's like the smarter model is just has more intelligence embedded in it.
So it has to do less, um, test time compute.
So it doesn't have to spend as many thinking tokens.
And so like Kimmy, because of that is going to be slower and it's going to use more tokens.
And so even if it's cheaper, if it's using more tokens, there's some crossover where
it actually becomes more expensive.
And so on the like, you know, per task or cost per task kind of metric that basically
ignores the amount of reasoning tokens or like incorporates that, then I don't think
it's quite as good as the frontier shows.
And like, I don't know, have you guys ever used how extensively have you used the open
models?
Like, like Kimmy K two or 2.5 wasn't nearly this hyped, but like people were saying that
it was as good as like sonnet back in the day when I was using sonnet a lot.
And I would use Kimmy and it was like so much dumber and noticeably dumber, and it was really,
really bad at using tools.
So it would just like, I'd send it off to do something.
And then it would just be like, ah, I don't know how to do this.
And it like has access to the MCP or, you know, there's just like stuff that it could
be doing and I have to product to do it.
And that kind of soured me on open models for a while.
I mean, Jackson, you're like, what's your experience with open models?
I guess you're mostly using run local, but is it similar to Tyler or, uh, I've never
read anything about how good people think Quinn three or GLM 4.7 are, but they're not
great and they're the only ones my computer can handle.
Uh, yeah, I can't even compare them to a model because I've been using such good models for
like the last few months.
And like my brain is like a little hamster wheel, like once it spins, it's gone.
So all I can say is that the open models I've used are not great, like not good enough for
me to be worth my time.
Yeah, I'm with you.
I had a minor meltdown over Claude guardrails yesterday.
Uh, nothing, nothing suspect.
All right.
related.
No, uh, I just, I'm a man with a lot of like eclectic, potentially on-chain interests.
Okay.
And, uh, yeah, it was just, uh, I was just like getting really annoyed, you know, getting
silently knocked down to 4.8.
And so I signed up to maple AI and they have, uh, Kimmy, I think he's at 2.6, uh, and one
of the Quinn's as well.
And yeah, I like, I gave it, I gave it a shot.
Um, but yeah, the, like the Delta is really noticeable.
You definitely lose something, uh, for, for not being constrained by the Claude guardrails.
Yeah.
I feel like the, um, the GPT guardrails are less annoying and also you don't have guardrails
on Opus, which Opus is still probably much better than Kimmy.
I think in practice, I would, I would guess, um, but yeah, you were mentioning Chris that
you thought that like GPT is good at coding, but it's like less of a bro than Claude.
Yeah.
Have you just become, you know, very accustomed to Claude's, Claude-isms and like you feel
like you have a nice friend there and then you go to GPT and GPT is like this cold calculating
like personality list AI and you're just like, can't get along with them, but you could delegate
work to them.
Are you asking if I have developed a Jackson style parasocial relationship with Claude?
Is that the question?
Um, not, not imply quite Jackson level because I think that's like extreme.
Like I think that there's a little bit of like, uh, almost like quasi-romantic, but
like, there's nothing to be ashamed on a physical level.
Yeah.
We all enjoy AI on our own way.
Okay.
Yeah.
Don't judge that.
You know?
Yeah.
I think we should all be free to enjoy AI however we want.
Um, but yeah, I, I do, I think, I think Claude is a cool guy.
Um, and I, I don't know how they've achieved that.
Like I'm not particularly an EA person and I feel like a lot of Claude's, you know, philosophy
and the methodology for training Claude is downstream of that.
Um, but I guess I wouldn't use cool guy to describe Claude.
I feel like a lot of like hall monitor energy.
And then, um, I do think Claude is a better writer and has like more human kind of feeling
to it, but I don't necessarily like vibe with the personality, but like I appreciate it
almost more than something without personality.
So it's like some personality is better than no personality, but I still think that Claude
is kind of a dweeb sometimes.
Yeah.
I stamped that.
He's an eager beaver.
Whereas codex is like the most cracked programmer you've ever met who just does exactly what
you say.
Um, yeah.
But you want that sometimes.
Sometimes you do, but sometimes I want, I want to like riffle, I want to be like, Hey,
Claude, what do you think about this?
Like, should we do it this way?
Should we do it that way?
And then, you know, Claude will protect my feelings.
Like he won't be like, no, that's wrong.
He'll be like, Oh, we're up five bucks boys.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Oh, we had done a hundred X. Like Claude told us, we would be up a hundred dollars right
now because we'd be 20 X the leverage from where we are now.
So we'd be up a hundo.
Five X leverage is this is why we can't have Claude running purple fortune.
I hereby want to put it to vote that we like have to have some kind of like, has to be
like either an unhinged, like Kimmy AI that, that does purple fortune, or at least a GPT
that we think is going to do what we tell it to.
We got to use a free, you know, local model, Chris, the dumbest, the dumbest local model
you can, the smallest and just let it go wild, like a lot of parameters.
Yeah, speaking about chat or like GPT versus Claude, I ran an experiment today with like
a pretty difficult, um, problem, um, like coding problem because that's my job.
And I was like, basically I made Fable do it and I made GPT 5.6 to it because I needed
to talk about GPT 5.6 on the pod today.
So they ran and the results are that Fable one-shotted it like a champ as it always does,
but it took, I believe three times as long in terms of like a clock time.
Yeah.
In terms of clock time.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And it costs about three times as much as well.
Um, so all that to say that Fable is still rocking it on GPT 5.6, but.
So GPT 5.6 didn't one shot it, it needed some more steering.
Is that what you're saying?
It thought it one shot at it in like 32 minutes, but it was wrong.
And how did you discover it was wrong?
Obviously not viewing the code.
So you asked Fable to ask if GPT was wrong.
Uh, I'll be honest.
So I looked at the code a little bit and then I got Opus 4.8 doesn't be the judge.
I think the anthropic models are like excellent managers, uh, that like overbearing whole
monitor types, uh, they're willing to talk smack about codecs as well.
Like, like Ford will just be like, yeah, let me kill these silly codecs models that are
ruining my code base.
Um, yeah.
Yeah.
I recognize I should have gotten like five unbiased AI reviewers to review the two AIs
code.
Yeah.
Did you have a GPT review the Fable code?
No, you only had Opus.
This is like, uh, it isn't a jury of peers here that you're constructing.
This is a biased, you know, jury.
That's true.
Yeah.
I should have done.
I object to this test.
You object to this test.
Well, the census from what people say is the 5.6 is fast.
It's punchy, but like, you kind of have to tell it what to do.
And I'm at the point with AI where like, I just tell like five tables what to do.
And then I like zone out for awhile.
And then I come back and they've done everything I want.
And maybe I'm a little bit too lazy and I, uh, I do a mix of that and like distributing
jobs from Babel to sonnets.
Um, and that's kind of where I think a chat GPT 5.6 comes in.
And I think that's what Chris, you say you use it for is for actual task execution for
the speed.
Is that right?
Yeah, exactly.
Like if the task is quite well scoped and I just need it to be done correctly, like
letter correctly, I think 5.6 is good for that.
But it's not a gig of brain.
I'm going to figure out all the ambiguities that you didn't lay out to me directly.
Totally.
And like, even like the pull request descriptions are like, they're so terse it like assumes
so much knowledge.
I'm like, dude, I don't like lay it out for me a little bit.
Like I, I didn't read this.
Like I asked you to do it.
So like, you know, I need you to do my job and explain to me what the job was.
Um, yeah, I'll get, I'll bring you back on the next spot though.
And if, if Opus 4.8 misrepresented the competition, I'll let you guys know.
But for now, okay, we trust.
And then kind of similar conversation, the cost, you know, I think people talk about
are these companies profitable?
How are they going to make money?
And I'm kind of starting to see my costs rise.
What about you guys?
I mean, Fable is so expensive.
Like I think that my costs went way up when I started using it.
That being said, it is probably worth it because it does noticeably better work than Opus.
It's nice that I don't pay for it myself that my employer pays for it all.
And that is reflected in my increased productivity.
So I mean, they were supposed to take Fable off the $200 max plan, I'm pretty sure five
days ago, and they keep extending it for five days, obviously, because they need to compete
with other models.
So I think the current five day extension might end in two days.
That's, that's what I think.
So for any person out there, yeah, they need to make up for the government, rugging the
crap out of us, you know, like we miss some days from the original deadline, right?
That's so true.
I think they're mostly just caught in a competitive dynamic against open AI, where like open AI
is going a little bit harder on the usage.
And so they like need to kind of keep up.
And the rumor is that they were going to launch a new Opus, I think, soon and then use that
to wean people off of Fable within the plan.
Do you have a personal like clog or GPT subscription?
I guess Chris, you have a Maple subscription now.
Yeah, I I'm out of control, dude.
It's like, I think I spend more on AI than food at this point.
Yeah, I've clawed and now Maple.
That's it.
I used to have a 200 clawed.
Yeah, I have a 200 clawed.
I'm out of control, dude.
I'm like, do you max it out?
Do you get like limited from your usage?
I try to max it out of principle, you know, like just to use as much.
Water as possible, but sometimes I fall short.
You know, the water thing is crazy.
I hope we haven't talked about on the podcast, but quick side note, I like go home to Georgia
and I'm like telling my family who live in the suburbs of Atlanta, man, I so awesome.
It's like way smarter than me.
I'm useless now.
And then they're like, but what about the water?
And I'm like, what about the water?
Are they like, do you want to go golfing this weekend, by the way, and like eat some almonds?
Yeah, dude, the targeted like hate news or whatever is so weird in the world.
I mean, do we even want to touch on the evaporative cooling?
Like reason for that, I guess rumor or like piece of news or like, we just let our listeners
like let them be confused.
If anyone can concisely state why the water concern is not legit, that would be fire.
Okay.
It seems like I volunteered myself.
My understanding is that some early versions, I want to like drain Lake Michigan.
That's what it is.
Tyler called it the astralification of the US.
Yeah.
That's his goal.
No, no, no.
I think like my understanding is early versions of these data centers that get slapped together
really quickly, like obviously, you know, they need electricity and they need to get
rid of waste heat, right?
Like that's a big problem in computing.
And so early versions use evaporative cooling, which obviously, you know, you put the water
somewhere, it gets hot, it evaporates and gets rid of the heat.
Um, it seems like, you know, more and more sophisticated versions of these data centers
are doing what they've done for a long time, which is closed loop systems where, you know,
the water gets hot and then gets cooled and then in a loop and, uh, yeah, therefore users
substantially less water.
So that's my understanding of how, how that came to be.
And then back to the AI cost thing, uh, cause I had some interesting numbers that I noticed.
It kind of seems like the way they're making money to me is they're making better models
that are like undeniably better.
So then you use them and they could just cost more.
They both like use more tokens because the context windows are better and, um, they have
like a higher charge rate.
And then like for me personally, they've also gotten a lot more addicting.
Like I find that I'm, I'm using them a lot more, but that's kind of a more personal thing.
I think the, the real cost increases like them releasing new models.
You go into the new models.
I think that net increases your spend if you're spending the same amount of time working.
I don't know.
What do you guys think?
Have you looked into your cost trends as you've gone from like sonnet opus cable?
It's hard to like untangle.
Yeah.
Like why am I using it more because the models are much better or because I've just been
using AI now for like six months and the depth of my power user, like all this stuff that
I shoved through it now is just so extreme.
And I feel like it's probably a little bit of both.
Like you give it more because it's so useful, but also like more and more of these tasks
and the, like the work scope of what I give it has just increased a bunch as well.
And now that's just like stuff that's built into my day.
But yeah, it's kind of like, I, you hear about some other companies and they're like, like
I think like Uber, there was a thing about how they limit, I think employees to like
$200 of tokens a week.
I do not know what I would do if I was limited to 200 tokens a week.
What are they doing?
Are they really slack with their eyes?
Like what are they doing?
Yeah.
Are they like a git push with a sonnet?
That's so gross.
Like their fingies?
Like, yeah, what's going on?
I'm not going to say numbers, but yeah, I'm not under the 200 a week personally.
I think I could get back to it.
I don't even know.
How would you ration yourself if you had to go from current to 200 a week?
Like would you use shittier models?
Would you do less work?
Would you just do stuff more by hand or is there a whole like types of tasks that you
wouldn't have it do?
That's kind of all of it.
I mean, I know exactly what I would do is I would take it back to sonnet, which was good
enough at executing tasks that I define well.
And then I would do all the thinking work that I've off boarded to fable since then.
So you do you'd think for yourself again.
Yeah.
I'm going to become an empty blob and an empty shell.
My fable is my only representation shortly.
Please don't release a better bottle.
I joke that I'm just like a context window extender for fable.
Like he puts stuff in here and then I like get it back to him when he needs it, you know,
like a rag database.
Empirically, definitely producing more able to produce a lot more and able to parallelize
across multiple tasks a lot better overlay GitHub contributions from 2026 and note when
I switched Opus and Babel and it becomes dark green.
This is not a flex.
It is only to show that like, yes, we're spending more or I'm spending more, but also I'm producing
more.
So, you know, it is it is working.
Yeah, there's no sorry to commits cleanly like translate to, you know, quality and like
impact.
Yes.
In the in my case, because I'm not doing like commits for the sake of commits, I'm doing
I mean, you can trust me just like you could trust me on all things.
What are you saying about my commits, dude?
What are you saying?
Do you have something to say?
Yeah, I didn't even look at your stats.
There's no way.
There's no way I could have produced from a product perspective what I produced in the
last year and a half without a there's no chance no shot, so.
It is really hard to generate a lot of slop by hand.
Well, I also I was quite good at that as well.
So you probably have a much Yeah, that was an excellent joke.
And it hit home pretty hard.
I was like, Oh, that's exactly what I am.
Do you think in the future you're going to have to like exercise your mind in the way
that you like go to the gym and lift weights because you're like, Oh, my, my thinking faculties
are going to atrophy if I don't like occasionally do some stuff to think for myself.
I do feel like some of my skills are getting like fuzzier, like the thought of like writing
a big long document on my own with no help is like terrifying because like that sounds
so boring and I would just like sit there and struggle to think of how I want to phrase
something or like what's the right word for this moment and it's just like tedious but
yeah, I probably used to be better at that and now it'd be tough.
I hear you.
Yeah, Chris.
Can you write a compiling like Kotlin state machine right now at this moment Kotlin.
I don't think I can assign a Kotlin variable right now if that's what you're asking.
Some other language like Rust or Golang.
Yeah, I probably I make it work it take me a couple of tries that I'm definitely like
out of whack.
Yeah, I was just like, you know, I was pretty good at the coding interviews that like writing
syntactically correct fast code, but like it I haven't done it in so long and I know
for sure I couldn't do Kotlin.
I don't I just mentioned this language totally randomly, by the way, I don't think I can
I could do it, which is yeah, exactly what you're saying, Tyler, like I would have been
able to do it, but I don't need to anymore.
Like let's say Python, I could write Python and it's like writing English.
So it's still really easy to remember and like writing a doc writing a doc is so like
two years ago, man, you just tell the tell the AI, don't tell anybody we're working
on.
Yeah, proliferation of like work slop is definitely a problem.
And I think I've been guilty of this to some extent.
I feel like the pressures that you're put on and in these workplaces where everyone
is adopting AI, it's just like, you're expected to do more and like cover more surface area
because you can like automate a lot of stuff and you can use AI to like scale yourself
in terms of like monitoring slack and monitoring all this multiple projects.
But then you kind of need to like, if you get something coming in, you need to like
turn it and get it out like as soon as you can just move on to the next thing.
And that lends itself to just like delegating to AI, hopefully doing like a quick once over
read, making sure it hits your quality bar, and then like putting it out there.
And then probably your coworker is like, Tyler, just send me this doc, Claude, can you go
read it and summarize it for me?
So it's like, just this, the doc is like this, like in intermediate artifact that just helps
the AIs interface with each other.
But yeah, like the proliferation of work slop, I like yearn for going back to the artisanal
time where I could like spend time and write something and put it in my own voice.
And it didn't have all the tells of being AI generated.
And I was like, very proud of it, but it's like, who has time to grind at that level
these days?
I think the reward functions are probably broken in like a lot of places right now where
like, you know, it's like, who cares how we get up the mountain, like the mountains there,
we're seeing other people get up the mountain, we just got to scramble.
But I think in the limit, it like maybe a little bit of the handcrafted artisanal nature
of work returns, right?
When I think like, you know, the quality bar is starting to drop at some like apps I use
on the day to day.
And I'm noticing more subtle bugs.
And I think, yeah, I think like, I think strategy and like, being deliberate comes back slowly.
But I think we have to go through this hill climb of scrambling up fable to get there.
We have to go through the great winter of slop before we can emerge into a beautiful
spring of artisanal docs and handwritten Kotlin code.
Yeah, we just have to tread water, you just have to keep our head above the slop.
I believe, yeah.
Those days are over boys.
Yeah, back on like the exercising your mind thing, like, I think we'll like see a decline
in our minds.
I'll need some studies to show me why I need my mind to be sharp before I am compelled
to sharpen it up, I think.
Do you read studies that are like, you need to have big muscles, and then you're like,
that's the reason you go to the gym and lift weights, Jackson?
Or do you do it because you're like, tight, I have big muscles, I like the way this feels,
and I like that I can like lift stuff in a non taxing way.
Like having a smart mind, I think, feels good.
Yeah, I'm just kind of extrapolating.
I imagine it feels good to have a smart mind.
I can't speak from experience, but.
And you guys are so humble and upfront about your intelligence.
I don't think I've commented on my own at all, but this feeling, well, hey, I never
said I was smart.
I would never say that.
Yeah, you can keep the humble train going for the AI training.
I don't know, I guess like, I think if I have intellectual hobbies, like I'm working on
my Spanish and my Korean, like then I'll do it.
But I don't think if it's like for the sake of having a sharp mind, like I'm like, I used
to be really good at mental math.
And after like, how many years, six years out of college, I can't multiply like three
digit numbers anymore in my head.
And sometimes I'm like, should I do it just for the sake of being like a calculator?
And the answer is no, because it doesn't give me anything.
So Spanish and like Korean too, I mean, I guess in some abstract sense, maybe it was
good at some time to be good at like mentally, um, multiplying numbers together.
That rules though.
Can we say, can we say that rules?
I think that rules.
I've never done that.
Have you done that Tyler?
No, no, not at that level.
Although I did, I did some job interviews coming out of college for like options trading
and they, they like would put me in a room and like ask me shit like that.
And I like felt, or they'd ask me like these like random brain teasers and I'd just be
like, bro, what?
Like, I'm not going to think about this interviews and that's what they are.
Like first they're testing your mental math and then they were testing statistics.
And unfortunately I did not miss statistics.
I was kind of bad, but the mental math is fine.
Yeah.
Yeah, I spent probably 200 hours on lead codes, like quite, like quite consecutive and, and
how many monsters were consumed per hour of lead code.
There's like a 200 can monster, like, um, like chair that's been duct taped together
just out of the frame.
I don't believe that monster is the strongest, the strongest thing you were taking for that.
That's all I'm going to say.
Whoa, accusations.
Um, no, it was just, it was just, uh, a throne of white monster.
Um, but to your point, Jackson, like with the mental math, I, I feel like lead codes,
uh, sits in like a similar for me personally, like niche where I'm like, it's something
I had to do for job interviews and like to get better at my craft.
But in hindsight, I think like the type of like insane grinding on like just trying to
find the patterns in this list of like a hundred problems that you might get is like maybe
not actually the best use of like your time, uh, in terms of like, you know, if you want
to like build something interested in complicated, like interesting and complicated, like maybe
you're better off like doing a lecture series on game theory or something.
We could gangster right here, but kind of like what I think you're saying and what I
think I was saying is in response to Tyler's question about exercise in your mind, it sounds
like these AI's free up our mind to focus on the things we actually want to do.
Like no one wants to do leak code, but they might want to build something interesting
for Chris or they might want to speak to Spanish native people, you know?
Yeah, and George, there's a lot of a lot of Spanish people in charge.
So that's, that's our response.
Yeah.
Tyler, the way that I feel the atrophy happening most acutely, I feel is like, um, thinking
really quickly on my feet and then like verbalizing and like maybe having like debates and stuff
like that.
Like, I feel like in some meetings or circumstances where I'm talking to someone all, yeah, just
be a little bit slower than I would like.
And then afterwards I'll be like, oh, if I had just like connected that dot in the moment,
I would have like had that point.
Um, and that's probably also a function of, uh, working remotely and not having like quite
as many built-in social interactions in my life as I used to.
So maybe that's just as much of the atrophy there as it is from like me talking to AI
all day.
Like if we, yeah, if I was in an office or if I was working for a company that required
me to be in the office, would I actually be talking to people all day or would I still
just be talking to an AI and just like swap rambling into the terminal, into the whisper
terminal window as well.
Here's what you do.
We can, we can get your quippiness back.
You turn on fable to do your work and then you go and you get your baby and you put on
voice to text, um, like conversation AI on grok, put on a lady's voice, put your baby
in front of the camera and just like chat with chat with her.
No, I think this podcast is my, uh, this is my lead code.
This is sharpening my mind and the, and yeah, oh, they, they let you do that, uh, of, of
smart people, whether it be Chris or whether it be swag dog, you guys are my, my sharpeners,
they let you talk to people, man.
They just put me in a room with a computer and they say, invert a binary tree.
Like that's been my career up until this point did crazy.
I think the podcast is evidence per all of your super famous shorts, Tyler, that you're
still as sharp as ever.
If you're any sharper, you'd be breaking YouTube's algorithm.
Yeah.
I'm a little worried.
Oh, we're about to break 10.
Jeez.
It just popped from six.
It was six, like two minutes ago.
This time you need to, you need to do the next one.
I think that Jared just got wrecked on chain again.
And then we're getting a dividend from Cheeto, you know, something's happening on Solana.
For sure.
Hold on.
You're calling it Cheeto, but it's a J. What's going on?
Is that what it's called?
The ticker is JTO, but the token is Cheeto.
So Cheeto, I think controls Solana staking.
And the way that Solana transactions are broadcasted is at an epoch, which I think is every two
days, they decide which validator is going to get to construct which block.
So you know, ahead of time.
And Cheeto, so, you know, like each individual validator can like order the transactions
in whatever way they want.
And Cheeto, I think is, has an agreement on how to order the transactions and funnel it
to one meb bot.
There's one meb bot.
So I don't have an opinion about that.
But yeah.
Yeah.
It's, I guess it's like a monopoly, right?
I guess on the, on the chain.
Some would say.
Some would say that's a monopoly.
Yes.
But maybe it's for the best.
Cause it's giving back to the people.
Just sounds like a government tax, basically, I'm there.
Yeah.
It's giving some back.
We can say that.
Oh, okay.
How much do you, what's the split?
10.
Now it's back down higher bar than I do.
One, I guess I just thought of this.
Why is there even MEV on Solana, like if the, the, I guess the concern about MEV is that
it causes like an incentive to reorg, right?
But then if they decide who makes the blocks two days in advance and it's like slotted
in, then are there no like reorgs because somebody just like, you know, proposes a block
on their slot and then they move on.
And so why does there need to be this GTO entity?
Well the answer is bribes knowing who is going to be able to order the transaction two days
in advance means you know who to bribe, right?
So my understanding is, and I'm not big across Solana MEV because you know, I don't have
connections in that world.
My understanding is GTO works in that space somehow.
The specifics allude me.
Yeah, I have no idea.
It was just something that seemed to me.
Is GTO kind of like an end game for like movable chains or is there like an end game where
like one company or one entity ends up being the MEV?
Like that's kind of what Jared is now, right?
And then they have this thing called Flashbots that I think it's a way for people like Jared
to submit MEV opportunities to this like pool and then validators who participate in the
pool can then, you know, take those MEV bundles and incorporate them in the blocks.
And so everyone is kind of pulling from the same MEV pool and then that means that no validators
inherently like better at MEV than any other, right?
And so I guess GTO is just doing the same for Solana.
Maybe that answers my own question earlier is like the reason GTO exists is because even
though the block slots are predetermined if any one Solana block producer got like really
good at extracting MEV better than the other ones, then they would get more systematically
more revenue and then potentially like a greater share of the network and more validators and
then they would be producing more blocks, but that probably wouldn't happen on Solana
anyways because they could just like decide to like, oh, you're like becoming too powerful.
Okay, well, like, you know, we'll break you up a little bit to preserve the illusion of
being more distributed, right, and those are your words, not mine.
But AI.
I will say one of the utilities here of the Ethereum approach and I don't think it's perfect,
it might not even be good, but is there's like a free market for MEV, right?
So you can kind of like, the people have to compete or the MEV extractors have to compete
against each other for this, which necessarily, you know, drives their cut down.
It gives more to the validators as they're paying more and more gas to get in the top
of the block.
Whether that happens with Jito, I don't know.
Okay, cool.
Well, I think that's a good place to end the pod, we're at a good time.
I'm sorry that we keep baiting all of our listeners on the agent at commerce, but all
this crazy, awesome stuff is happening and we'd rather talk about it.
Is that like a signal that none of us are actually excited about agentic commerce, we're
all agentic commerce bearers?
I really want to talk about it personally, but as we said evergreen topics, we save them
until we need them.
I want to talk about it too, but for like bad reasons, like really terrible reasons,
like maybe we shouldn't talk about it, I don't know.
That's exactly why we should talk about it.
Because you're a bear and you're going to like, you know, make everyone a bear on agentic
commerce or because what are the bad reasons?
I don't spoil it, I don't spoil it, there are specific reasons, they're very specific.
Okay, tune in next time to figure out why Chris has a extreme grudge against the agentic
commerce.
He's plotting against the whole concept this whole intervening week.
All right, and we peace out at $10 up.
Very well, guests, everyone throw a wave.
Thank you, Gito.
All right.
Thank you, Gito, for sponsoring.